Geoff George

Chicago, IL 60626

Cell: (319) 330-8106 • E-mail: geoffdgeorge@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/geoff-george

Github: github.com/geoffdgeorge • Portfolio: geoffdgeorge.com

SKILLS

HTML

CSS (Flexbox and Grid) Vanilla JS (ES6)

Node

Express

MySQL

MongoDB

React

React Native

Expo

NativeBase

iQuery

Chart JS

Leaflet

Mongoose

Sequelize

Passport

Bootstrap

Scrum / Agile Processes

EDUCATION

Northwestern University School of Professional Studies

Evanston, IL Full-Stack Web Development

Professional Certification

University of Missouri

Columbia, MO M.A., Journalism GPA: 4.0/4.0

University of Iowa

lowa City, IA
B.A., Cinema & Literature
GPA: 3.66/4.0
Major GPA: 3.74/4.0
Dean's List: 5 semesters

President's List: 1 year

SUMMARY

Web developer and programmer with ten years of experience as a writer and editor, working on and brainstorming solutions for multiple projects at once. Can pick up the rules and syntax of new languages and libraries quickly and proficiently and can communicate them well to others.

PROJECTS

<u>Fridge2Table</u> — Developer, Authentication and React Native Lead — <u>GitHub</u>

June 2019-Present

Awards: First Place, Next Level Contest, beating out nearly 70 other entrants nationwide **Tools used:** React Native, Expo, NativeBase, Auth0, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, Cron

- -Working with a four-person development team to build a full-stack mobile app for tracking grocery items by category and expiration date, compatible with both Android and iOS and already available from the Google Play Store
- -Serving as the primary front-end developer, building client-side functionality and styling with React Native
- -Serving as the sole developer working with Auth0 to authenticate users

Patellr — Developer, Github Manager — GitHub

May 2019

Tools used: Vanilla JS, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, Passport, Handlebars, Chart JS, CSS Grid

- -Worked with a three-person development team to build a full-stack app for tracking knee-pain recovery
- -Served as the sole developer working with Passport to provide authenticated routing on the app's back end

Fresh Farm Recipes — Developer, Github Manager — GitHub

March 2019

Tools used: jQuery, Leaflet, Edamam API, USDA farmer's market API, Bootstrap

- -Worked with a four-person development team to build a multi-API-based app providing recipe recommendations from selected ingredients and listing and mapping nearby farmers' markets
- -Served as the sole developer working with Leaflet to accurately map the locations of farmers' markets

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Coding Boot Camp Teaching Assistant

July 2019-Present

Northwestern University, Chicago and Evanston, IL

- -Attending classes on an as-needed basis for an accelerated six-month web-development boot camp
- -Walking students as a group and one on one through various exercises in HTML5, CSS3, Git, Heroku, Bootstrap,
- JavaScript, jQuery, APIs, Firebase, AJAX, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express.js, Handlebars, and React
- -Collaborating with the instructor and supporting in-class lectures with contextual insights

Copy Editor / Senior Editor

Nov. 2010-June 2015 and May 2017-May 2019

Modern Counsel and American Builders Quarterly, Chicago, IL

- -Coordinated with executive-level clients in a variety of trades to determine angles for profile stories
- -Managed more than 30 freelance writers, assigning them stories and ensuring their deadlines were met
- -Oversaw in-house editorial, design, and photography staff for each magazine
- -Shaped and copy edited 55-75 stories per quarterly issue cycle using the Chicago Manual of Style
- -Wrote feature-length stories, sidebars, and calendar items, as needed, and managed social media and web content

Newsletter Content Manager

Oct. 2016-May 2017

BuiltWorlds, Chicago, IL

- -Wrote, designed, and scheduled eight newsletters per month and tracked analytics for each
- -Pitched and wrote stories and edited and posted all stories from contract writers according to AP style